So in my free time outside of Twitter
خلال وقت فراغي بعيدا عن توتر
I experiment a little bit
أقوم بتجارب بسيطة
with telling stories online, experimenting
برواية القصص اون لاين , أقوم بتجارب
with what we can do with new digital tools.
عن ما نستطيع ان نفعله بالتكنولوجيا الجديدة
And in my job at Twitter,
في عملي في تويتر
I actually spent a little bit of time
أقضي في الحقيقة قليل من وقتي
working with authors and storytellers as well,
بالعمل مع المؤلفين وراويّ القصص أيضاً
helping to expand out the bounds
للمساعدة في توسيع حدود
of what people are experimenting with.
الاشياء التي يقومون الناس بالتجارب معها
And I want to talk through some examples today
وسأتحدث اليوم عن بعض الأمثلة
of things that people have done
عن الأشياء التي عملها الناس
that I think are really fascinating
والتي أظن انها فعلاً مبهرة
using flexible identity and anonymity on the web
استخدام هوية متعددة ومجهولة على الويب
and blurring the lines between fact and fiction.
وتضليل الخطوط بين الحقيقة والخيال
But I want to start and go back to the 1930s.
لكن سأبدأ من عام 1930
Long before a little thing called Twitter,
قديماً حتى قبل الشيء المسمى تويتر
radio brought us broadcasts
الراديو قدم لنا البث
and connected millions of people
وربط الملايين من الناس
to single points of broadcast.
بنقطة بث واحدة
And from those single points emanated stories.
ومن هذه النقطة الواحدة انطلقت القصص
Some of them were familiar stories.
بعضها مألوف
Some of them were new stories.
والاخرى قصص جديدة
And for a while they were familiar formats,
ولفترة كانت الصيغ مألوفة
but then radio began to evolve its own
لكن بعد ذلك, قام الراديو يطور
unique formats specific to that medium.
أسلوب مميز خاص للنشر الإذاعي
Think about episodes that happened live on radio.
فكر في حلقة تمت إذاعتها على الهواء
Combining the live play
الجمع بين العرض الحي
and the serialization of written fiction,
والتسلسل الخيالي للقصة
you get this new format.
فتحصل أنت على هذا الأسلوب الجديد
And the reason why I bring up radio is that I think
والسبب الذي جعلني اقدم الراديو هو أني أظن
radio is a great example of how a new medium
أن الراديو هو مثال عظيم في كيف الوسيلة الجديدة
defines new formats which then define new stories.
تعرف الأسلوب الجديد والذي بعد ذلك عرفنا على قصص جديدة
And of course, today, we have an entirely new
وبالطبع, اليوم , لدينا بشكل جديد وكامل
medium to play with,
وسيلة لنتعامل معها
which is this online world.
وهو عالم الانترنت
This is the map of verified users on Twitter
هذه خريطة الحسابات المثبتة على تويتر
and the connections between them.
والعلاقات بينهم
There are thousands upon thousands of them.
هناك ألوف وألوف منهم
Every single one of these points
كل واحد من هؤلاء النقاط
is its own broadcaster.
هو صاحب قناة بث
We've gone to this world of many to many,
وصلنا إلى عالم به الكثير والكثير
where access to the tools is the only barrier to broadcasting.
الوقت الذي تكون فيه محاولة الحصول على الادوات هو الحاجز الوحيد للبث
And I think that we should start to see
وأعتقد أننا يجب أن نبدأ برؤية
wildly new formats emerge
متوسعة لإنبثاق اساليب جديدة
as people learn how to tell stories in this new medium.
ما دام الناس يتعلمون كيف يحكون القصص من خلال هذه القنوات
I actually believe that we are in a wide open frontier
في الواقع انا اعتقد اننا في حدود مفتوح
for creative experimentation, if you will,
لتجارب ذكية
that we've explored and begun to settle
لقد اكتشفنا وبدأنا في تسوية
this wild land of the Internet
هذه المساحة الواسعة من الأنترنت
and are now just getting ready
والآن نحن نقوم بالاستعداد
to start to build structures on it,
لنبدأ بناء كيان عليها
and those structures are the new formats
وهذا الكيان هو الأساليب الجديدة
of storytelling that the Internet will allow us to create.
لرواية القصص التي يسمح لنا الأنترنت بإنشائها
I believe this starts with an evolution
أؤمن أن هذه البدايات التطويرية
of existing methods.
لأساليب موجودة
The short story, for example,
القصة القصيرة , على سبيل المثال
people are saying that the short story
الناس يقولون ان القصة القصيرة
is experiencing a renaissance of sorts
هي اختبار لنهضة من نوعا ما
thanks to e-readers, digital marketplaces.
الشكر لقارئ الكتب الالكترونية, والسوق الالكتروني
One writer, Hugh Howey, experimented
الكاتب هيو هاوي قام بتجربة
with short stories on Amazon
مع القصص القصيرة على امازون
by releasing one very short story called "Wool."
بإطلاق قصة قصيرة جداً أسمها (وول)
And he actually says that he didn't intend
وهو في الواقع قال انه لم يأخذ
for "Wool" to become a series,
(وول) على محمل الجد
but that the audience loved the first story so much
لكن الجمهور أحب القصة الأولى بشدة
they demanded more, and so he gave them more.
وطالب بالمزيد, ولذلك قام بكتابة المزيد
He gave them "Wool 2," which was a little bit longer than the first one,
كتب (وول2), والذي كان أكبر قليلاً من القصة الأولى
"Wool 3," which was even longer,
(وول3) والذي كان أطول
culminating in "Wool 5,"
وأنتهت السلسلة بقصة (وول5)
which was a 60,000-word novel.
والتي كانت رواية من 60.000 كلمة
I think Howey was able to do all of this because
أعتقد ان هاوي كان بإمكانه عمل كل هذا بسبب
he had the quick feedback system of e-books.
أنه كان لديه نظام سريع لمعرفة ردود الافعال للكتب الالكترونية
He was able to write and publish
كانت لديه الامكانية للكتابة والنشر
in relatively short order.
في وقت قصير نسبياً
There was no mediator between him and the audience.
كان لا يوجد وسيط بينه وبين الجمهور
It was just him directly connected with his audience
كان هو فقط مرتبط بالجمهور
and building on the feedback and enthusiasm
ويبني على ردود الافعال وحماسة الجمهور
that they were giving him.
هذا ما كانوا يعطونه
So this whole project was an experiment.
كامل هذا المشروع كان اختبار
It started with the one short story,
بدأ بقصة قصيرة واحدة
and I think the experimentation actually became
وأعتقد ان القيام بالتجارب اصبح في الواقع
a part of Howey's format.
جزء من أسلوب (هاوي)
And that's something that this medium enabled,
وهذا شيء تسمح به هذه الوسيلة
was experimentation being a part of the format itself.
القيام بالتجارب كان جزء من الأسلوب نفسه
This is a short story by the author Jennifer Egan
هذه قصة قصيرة من تأليف جينيفر إيقن
called "Black Box."
تسمى "الصندوق الأسود"
It was originally written
كتبت في الأصل
specifically with Twitter in mind.
خصصياً وتويتر في البال
Egan convinced The New Yorker
ايقن أقنعت نيويوركر
to start a New Yorker fiction account
لتبدأ حساب نيويوركر الخيالي
from which they could tweet
منها يستطيعون التغريد
all of these lines that she created.
عن الأسطر التي تنشئها هي
Now Twitter, of course, has a 140-character limit.
تويتر الان , بالطبع, محدود بـ 140 حرف
Egan mocked that up just writing manually
ايقن كرّست وقتها لتكتب يدوياً
in this storyboard sketchbook,
على دفتر رسم القصة المصورة
used the physical space constraints
بإستخدام القيود الطبيعية في المساحة
of those storyboard squares
لتلك المربعات في القصة المصورة
to write each individual tweet,
لكتابة كل تغريدة فردية
and those tweets ended up becoming
وهذه التغريدات انتهى بها الحال لأن تصبح
over 600 of them that were serialized by The New Yorker.
أكثر من 600 منها تم نشرها بواسطة نيويوركر
Every night, at 8 p.m., you could tune in
كل ليلة, الساعة 8 مساءاً, تستطيع متابعة
to a short story from The New Yorker's fiction account.
قصة قصيرة من حساب نيويوركر الخيالي
I think that's pretty exciting:
أعتقد ان هذا محمس جداً
tune-in literary fiction.
متابعة الخيال الأدبي
The experience of Egan's story, of course,
تجربة قصة ايقن , بالتأكيد
like anything on Twitter, there were multiple ways to experience it.
كأي شيء آخر في تويتر, كان يوجد الكثير من الطرق الاخرى لإختبارها
You could scroll back through it,
بإمكاننا أن نعيد النظر خلالها
but interestingly, if you were watching it live,
ومن المثير للإهتمام, إذا كنت تشاهدها مباشرة
there was this suspense that built
فهناك تشويق تم بناءه
because the actual tweets,
بسبب التغريدات الفعلية
you had no control over when you would read them.
لا تستطيع التحكم بنفسك وانت تقرأها
They were coming at a pretty regular clip,
لأنها تأتي على شكل مقطع روتيني
but as the story was building,
لكن على حسب بناية القصة
normally, as a reader, you control how fast you move through a text,
العادة, كقارئ, ستتحكم بسرعة التحرك خلال النص
but in this case, The New Yorker did,
لكن في هذه الحالة, (ذا نيويوركر) تفعل ذلك
and they were sending you bit by bit by bit,
هم يرسلونها لك واحدة بواحدة بواحدة
and you had this suspense of waiting for the next line.
وأنت لديك هذا التشويق الذي يجعلك تنتظر السطر التالي
Another great example of fiction
مثال جيد آخر للخيال
and the short story on Twitter,
والقصة القصيرة على تويتر
Elliott Holt is an author who wrote a story called "Evidence."
إليوت هولت, مؤلفة كتب قصة تسمى (ايفدنس) [الدليل]
It began with this tweet: "On November 28
تبدأ بهذه التغريدة, في نوفمبر 28
at 10:13 p.m.,
الساعة 10:13 مساءاً
a woman identified as Miranda Brown,
امرأة تعرف بـ(ميراندا براون)
44, of Brooklyn, fell to her death
44, من بروكلين, سقطت ميتة
from the roof of a Manhattan hotel."
من السقف في فندق (مانهاتن)
It begins in Elliott's voice,
تبدأ بصوت اليوت
but then Elliott's voice recedes,
لكن صوت (اليوت) يتراجع
and we hear the voices of Elsa, Margot and Simon,
ثم نسمع صوت (إلسا), مارجوت, وسايمون
characters that Elliott created on Twitter
شخصيات ابتكرتها (اليوت) على تويتر
specifically to tell this story,
خصيصاً لتحكى على تويتر
a story from multiple perspectives
قصة من مشاهد متعددة
leading up to this moment at 10:13 p.m.
تقودك إلى هذه اللحظة عند الساعة 10:13 مساءاً
when this woman falls to her death.
عندما سقطت المرأة ميتة
These three characters brought an authentic vision
هذه الثلاث شخصيات شكلّت رؤية حقيقية
from multiple perspectives.
من مشاهد متعددة
One reviewer called Elliott's story
مشاهد واحد اسمه, قصة (اليوت)
"Twitter fiction done right," because she did.
"خيال تويتر متقن جيداً," لأنها فعلتها
She captured that voice
هي أسرت هذا الصوت
and she had multiple characters and it happened in real time.
لديها شخصيات متعددة تم عملها على الواقع الحقيقي
Interestingly, though, it wasn't just
ومن المثير للإهتمام, رغماً عن ذلك, لم يكن فقط
Twitter as a distribution mechanism.
تويتر كتقنية نشر
It was also Twitter as a production mechanism.
بل كان أيضاً تقنية انتاج
Elliott told me later
اليوت أخبرتني بعد ذلك
she wrote the whole thing with her thumbs.
أنها كتبت هذا كله بإبهامها
She laid on the couch and just went back and forth
أستقلت على أريكتها وأخذت تتردد ذهاباً وإياباً
between different characters
بين مختلف الشخصيات
tweeting out each line, line by line.
تغرد كل سطر , سطر بسطر
I think that this kind of spontaneous creation
اعتقد ان هذا نوع من إيجاد التشويق
of what was coming out of the characters' voices
من ما يخرج من أصوات الشخصيات
really lent an authenticity to the characters themselves,
فعلاً مدت مصداقية لنفس الشخصيات
but also to this format that she had created
لكن أيضاً للأسلوب التي ابتكرته
of multiple perspectives in a single story on Twitter.
من مشاهد متعددة في قصة واحدة على تويتر
As you begin to play with flexible identity online,
كما تبدأ ببالتلاعب بالهويات على الانترنت
it gets even more interesting
انها اكثر إثارة
as you start to interact with the real world.
إذا بدأت تتفاعل مع العالم الحقيقي
Things like Invisible Obama
أشياء مثل اوباما الخفي
or the famous "binders full of women"
او (الملفات المليئة بالنساء) المشهور
that came up during the 2012 election cycle,
والذي ظهر خلال دورة الانتخابات في 2012
or even the fan fiction universe of "West Wing" Twitter
او حتى عالم هواة الخيال (ويست وينق) في تويتر
in which you have all of these accounts
والتي ستحصل على كل هذه الحسابات
for every single one of the characters in "The West Wing,"
لكل شخص واحد من شخصيات (ذا ويست وينق)
including the bird that taps at Josh Lyman's window
بالاضافة إلى الطائر الذي يطرق نافذة (ليمان)
in one single episode. (Laughter)
في واحدة من الحلقات
All of these are rapid iterations on a theme.
كل هذه تتكرر بشكل متسارع في الموضوع
They are creative people experimenting
هؤلاء هم أشخاص مبدعين يقومون بالتجارب
with the bounds of what is possible in this medium.
مع الحدود التي تسمح لهم في هذه الوسيلة
You look at something like "West Wing" Twitter,
تنظر إلى شيء ما مثل (ويست ونق) تويتر
in which you have these fictional characters
فيما تملك من هذه الشخصيات الخيالية
that engage with the real world.
التي تصطدم بالعالم الحقيقي
They comment on politics,
هم يعلقون على السياسة
they cry out against the evils of Congress.
هم يصرخون ضد شرور الكونجرس
Keep in mind, they're all Democrats.
لتتذكر هذا, كلهم ديمقراطيين
And they engage with the real world.
وهم يتشابكون مع العالم الحقيقي
They respond to it.
هم يستجيبون له
So once you take flexible identity,
متى ما حصلت على هوية متقلبة
anonymity, engagement with the real world,
مجهولة, مرتبطة مع العالم الحقيقي
and you move beyond simple homage or parody
وتتحرك وراء الاحترام أو السخرية
and you put these tools to work in telling a story,
وتضع هذه الادوات للعمل في قصة
that's when things get really interesting.
هنا عندما تكون مثيرة فعلاً
So during the Chicago mayoral election
خلال الانتخابات البلدية في شيكاغو
there was a parody account.
كان هناك حساب ساخر
It was Mayor Emanuel.
كان العمدة (ايمانويل)
It gave you everything you wanted from Rahm Emanuel,
كان يعطيك أي شيء تريده من (رام ايمانويل)
particularly in the expletive department.
عملياً في قسم الحشو
This foul-mouthed account
هذا الحساب السيء
followed the daily activities of the race,
تابع النشاطات اليومية للسباق
providing commentary as it went.
مع تقديم تعليق كما يسير الأمر
It followed all of the natural tropes
اتبع كل الاستعارات الطبيعية
of a good, solid Twitter parody account,
لحساب ساخر وثابت وجيد في تويتر
but then started to get weird.
ثم بدأ يتغير بشكل غريب
And as it progressed, it moved from this commentary
وكما تم تحليله, تحرك من هذا التعليق
to a multi-week, real-time science fiction epic
وبشكل اسبوعي وحقيقي إلى بطولات من الخيال العلمي
in which your protagonist, Rahm Emanuel,
والذي يكون بطل الرواية (رام ايمانيول)
engages in multi-dimensional travel on election day,
مشارك بالتنقل بأبعاد مختلفة في يوم الانتخابات
which is -- it didn't actually happen.
والتي في الحقيقة لم تحصل
I double checked the newspapers.
تحققت أكثر من مرة من الصحف
And then, very interestingly, it came to an end.
ثم وبكل اثارة, وصلت إلى النهاية
This is something that doesn't usually happen
هذا شيء لا يحصل العادة
with a Twitter parody account.
من حساب ساخر على تويتر
It ended, a true narrative conclusion.
انتهت , سرد حقيقي في النهاية
And so the author, Dan Sinker, who was a journalist,
والمؤلف (دان سنكر) والذي كان صحفي
who was completely anonymous this whole time,
والذي كان مجهول تماماً طيلة ذاك الوقت
I think Dan -- it made a lot of sense for him
اعتقد ان دان --- صنعت له ادراك هائل
to turn this into a book,
بتحويل هذا إلى كتاب
because it was a narrative format in the end,
لأنه كان أسلوب سردي في النهاية
and I think that turning it into a book
واعتقد ان ما حولها إلى كتاب
is representative of this idea that he had created something new
هو هذه الفكرة والتي ابتكرت شيء جديد
that needed to be translated into previous formats.
يحتاج إلى ترجمتها إلى اساليب قديمة
One of my favorite examples
واحد من أفضل الامثلة بالنسبة لي
of something that's happening on Twitter right now,
لشيء يحدث الان على تويتر
actually, is the very absurdist Crimer Show.
في الحقيقة , هو العبثي جداً (كرايمر شو)
Crimer Show tells the story
(كرايمر شو) يحكي قصة
of a supercriminal and a hapless detective
محقق جنائي بائس ومجرم كبير
that face off in this exceptionally strange lingo,
هذه المواجهة في اللغة الغريبة الاستثنائية
with all of the tropes of a television show.
مع كل الاستعارات في المستخدمة في مسلسل تلفزيوني
Crimer Show's creator has said that
مبتكر (كرايمر شو) قال
it is a parody of a popular type of show in the U.K.,
أنه حساب ساخر لمسلسل معروف في بريطانيا
but, man, is it weird.
لكن , أليس هذا غريب؟
And there are all these times where Crimer,
هناك الكثير من الاوقات حينما (كرايمر)
the supercriminal, does all of these TV things.
المجرم الكبير, يعمل كل ما يتم عمله في التلفزيون
He's always taking off his sunglasses
هو دائماً يخلع نظاراته الشمسية
or turning to the camera,
او يتوجه للكاميرا
but these things just happen in text.
لكن كل هذا يحدث في النص
I think borrowing all of these tropes from television
اعتقد استعارة كل هذه الاستعارات من التلفزيون
and additionally presenting each Crimer Show
بالاضافة إلى تقديم كل حلقة من (كرايمر شو)
as an episode, spelled E-P-P-A-S-O-D, "eppasod,"
بحروف (E-P-P-A-S-O-D, eppasod,)
presenting them as episodes
يتم تقديمها على شكل حلقات
really, it creates something new.
فعلاً , ابتكرت شيئاً جديداً
There is a new "eppasod" of Crimer Show
هناك حلقة جديدة من (كرايمر شو)
on Twitter pretty much every day,
على تويتر كل يوم
and they're archived that way.
وتتم أرشفتها بهذه الطريقة
And I think this is an interesting experiment in format.
وأعتقد انها تجربة مثيرة في الاسلوب
Something totally new has been created here
شيء جديد تماماً تم ابتكاره هنا
out of parodying something on television.
من السخرية من شيء ما على التلفزيون
I think in nonfiction real-time storytelling,
اعتقد في القصص الواقعية الحالية
there are a lot of really excellent examples as well.
يوجد الكثير من الامثلة الجيدة جداً
RealTimeWWII is an account
(RealTimeWWII) هو حساب
that documents what was happening on this day 60 years ago
يوثق كل شيء يحصل في نفس اليوم قبل 60 سنة
in exceptional detail, as if
في تفاصيل استثنائية, كما لو كنت
you were reading the news reports from that day.
تقرأ الأخبار في ذاك اليوم
And the author Teju Cole has done
والمؤلف (تاجو كول) كان قد انتهى
a lot of experimentation with putting a literary twist
من عمل الكثير من الاختبارات مع تحريف
on events of the news.
على احداث الاخبار
In this particular case, he's talking about drone strikes.
في هذه القضية تحديداً , هو يتحدث عن هجوم النحل
I think that in both of these examples,
اعتقد ان هذا يكون في هذين المثالين
you're beginning to see ways in which
أنت تبدأ في رؤية الطرق التي
people are telling stories with nonfiction content
يستخدمها الناس لرواية القصص الواقعية
that can be built into new types
بإمكان هذا ان تتم بنايته في نوع جديد
of fictional storytelling.
من رواية القصص الخيالية
So with real-time storytelling,
مع القصص الواقعية
blurring the lines between fact and fiction,
تعمية الخطوط بين الحقيقة والخيال
the real world and the digital world,
العالم الحقيقي والعالم الرقمي
flexible identity, anonymity,
هويات مرنة , ومجهولة
these are all tools that we have accessible to us,
هذه كلها ادوات يمكننا الوصول إليه
and I think that they're just the building blocks.
واعتقد انها مثل لبنات المباني
They are the bits that we use
إنها أشياء نستخدمها
to create the structures, the frames,
لإبتكار هياكل , إطارات
that then become our settlements on this
والتي سيصبح استقرارنا على
wide open frontier for creative experimentation.
مساحة حدود واسعة لإبتكار إنشاء التجارب
Thank you.
شكراً
(Applause)
(تصفيق)